statestreet.com 2019-07-23

# Privacy Notice | State Street Corporation

This Privacy Notice describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide through the State Street Bank and Trust Company (“State Street”) website and thought leadership mobile app (collectively, this “Site”), or various other offline means. This Privacy Notice applies to any personal information we may collect from you through this Site, independent of the device (e.g., mobile, computer) used to access this Site or various other offline means. 

  * Your Privacy on State Street’s Site
  * How we collect information
  * What information we may collect
  * Sensitive personal information
  * How we use and share your personal information
  * Marketing communications and your choices
  * Cookies and online tracking
  * How we transfer and store personal information
  * Where we protect your personal information
  * Your rights

## **Privacy on State Street’s Site**

State Street operates this Site to provide you with tools and resources to help you learn more about us. When you visit our Site, or otherwise interact with us offline, we want you to feel confident that we are committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information. By interacting with us offline, visiting this Site, and/or using the Services offered on or through this Site, or various other offline means (“Services”), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Notice (“Privacy Notice”), as they may be amended from time to time, and to State Street’s collection, use, processing, and disclosure of your information as described below. State Street may change this Privacy Notice at any time without prior notice to you. Any changes or updates will be effective immediately upon posting to the Site.

## **How we collect information**

We collect personal information in a variety of ways when you visit our website or when we provide you services including, but not limited to: various applications, third-party sources (such as social media networks), market business services, trade instructions, verbal instructions, and other documentation that you provide to us. We may also receive this information from firms that assist us in administering your account and processing transactions on your behalf or from agents or mandataries you may have designated to act on your behalf. We collect this information in order to service your account properly and provide you with the services you expect to receive. We limit our collection and use of personal information to that required for valid business purposes or to comply with applicable law.

## **What information we collect**

We collect and process the personal information you provide to us when you:

  * Register to use or use our Services via this Site and provide information required to use our Services.
  * Fill out forms on our Site.
  * Register or subscribe to our newsletters or conferences.
  * Ask us to authenticate you as an authorized user and ask us to facilitate communications between us that you request.
  * Contact State Street with a request.
  * Complete surveys issued by State Street (we will process information provided by you for research and monitoring purposes).
  * In email and other electronic messages between you and us.
  * Offline such as in-person, through paper forms, through the mail or other such means.
  * From our clients, affiliates or business partners who share information with us for the purpose of providing Services to you. 

State Street also may collect your IP address and information regarding the computer or mobile device used to access this Site, such as its operating system, unique identifier, and model name, as well as its user configurations and settings. And as discussed in detail below, we may also collect information relating to your use of the Site and our Services.

We may combine the information that we collect through the Site or Services with personal or other information that we obtain from third parties (such as social media networks or marketing partners) or that we collect from you in other contexts (such as when you email us, call us, or attend one of our events). If the information collected is about you or relates to you, or is combined with such information, State Street will treat it as personal information. We will retain information collected about you online for as long as permitted for legitimate business purposes.

## **Sensitive personal information**

State Street recognizes that certain jurisdictions have enacted laws that require higher protection of certain sensitive personal information. “Sensitive personal information” includes categories of personal data identified by European and other data privacy laws as requiring special treatment. This may include personal identity numbers; racial or ethnic origin; political opinions; religious, philosophical, or other similar beliefs; membership of a trade union or profession or trade association; physical or mental health; biometric or genetic data; sexual life; or criminal record (including suspected criminal activities). As a general rule, State Street does not require such sensitive personal information from you.

In the limited cases where we do seek to collect such information, we will seek to do so in accordance with applicable data privacy law requirements. If you choose to provide us with unsolicited sensitive personal information, you consent to us using the information, subject to applicable law as described in this Privacy Notice.

## **How we use and share personal information**

The information that we collect enables State Street to provide you with access to the Site and the Services you request, process online job applications, tailor the marketing of business services to our institutional customers, and to carry out other purposes which we describe to you at the point where the information is collected. The purposes for which your information may be processed include but are not limited to the following:

  * To offer you an enhanced, personalized online experience by enabling us to better tailor and personalize our Services.
  * To authenticate you as an authorized user and to facilitate communications between us that you request.
  * To fulfill your requests, including sending you white papers, newsletters, and other supplements and inviting you to events.
  * To contact you for marketing purposes in line with the applicable laws. (See the section below entitled “Marketing communications and your choices.”)
  * To operate our business in a prudent manner in accordance with industry standards and applicable law, which may include, in addition to supporting the Services, responding to inquiries and requests; preventing fraud; and monitoring and archiving communications.
  * To verify your identity or the identity of our clients or their controllers, owners or beneficial owners. 
  * To comply with any legal or regulatory requirements, pursue the legitimate interests of State Street and protect our legal position in the event of legal proceedings.
  * To fulfill any purpose for which you provide the information as we may describe at the time of collection or in our privacy policy. 
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and State Street.

State Street may disclose or share personal information to its affiliates for various purposes, as permitted by law, including in order for its affiliates to provide services.

State Street may also share personal information with government agencies, exchanges, or other self-regulatory organizations and law enforcement authorities as required or permitted by law, rule, regulation or legal process, including, without limitation, for governmental reporting or to enforce any rights State Street may have against you as necessary. Personal information about you that is collected on the Site, or in the course of the provision of Services, including any of your financial information, can become subject to the legal systems and laws in force in each state or country (a) where it is held, received or stored by you or us, (b) from where it is accessed by you or us, or (c) through which it passes. In addition, if you have an account at State Street, because your account(s) may include information about more than one individual and about your business relations with State Street and its affiliates, statements released to comply with legal process may contain information regarding your relationship with these individuals and with us and our affiliates.

State Street may disclose your personal information (i) at the request of a bank or other regulatory agency of competent jurisdiction or in connection with an examination of us by bank or other examiners; (ii) to our internal or external auditors or attorneys; (iii) when State Street believes disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (iv) if disclosure is necessary to protect the vital interests of a person.

State Street may disclose or share personal information to nonaffiliated third parties with whom it has contracted to perform services on its behalf. State Street requires its third-party servicers to agree to comply with appropriate privacy and security standards or to undertake to provide similar and appropriate levels of protection as State Street when processing personal information. In addition, State Street may share personal information and other information collected through the Site and the Services with a successor entity in the event of a merger, acquisition, or similar transaction.

## **Marketing communications and your choices**

State Street uses information collected on the Site and information obtained from third-party sources (such as social media networks) to market business services to our institutional customers. Specifically, we may collect, use, and/or share your information with our affiliates and service providers in order to provide specific information that you request, thought leadership materials, industry information, invitations to events and webinars, and other communications or solicitations (including, subject to the preferences you express through your interactions with our Site or when you request specific services, marketing communications), that we believe will be of interest to you. We target and tailor such communications based on your interaction with State Street’s websites, mobile apps, and emails; your inquiries; your participation in events or webinars; relevant social media activity; and other third-party data. No client proprietary information, and no information about any of the individuals or entities that your firm may service, will be collected, used, or shared for purposes of delivering these communications to you. By using the Site or voluntarily submitting your contact information on the Site, you consent to the use and sharing of your information for such purposes. You may, however, opt out of receiving such marketing communications by [clicking here](http://www.statestreet.com/content/ssbsr/en_US/email-preference-center.html) or by following the opt-out instructions contained in each communication.

## **Cookies and online tracking**

State Street may periodically collect information from you through automated means. When you browse the **** Site, use the Services, or read our emails or newsletters, we may use “cookies” or other online tracking mechanisms in order to provide better service, facilitate your use of the Site or Services, store online preferences, track usage of the Site or Services, including open and click-through rates of emails, tailor the marketing of business services to our institutional customers, or enhance security.

## **What are cookies?**

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information downloaded to your computer or device when you visit a site. Cookies are then sent back to the originating site on each subsequent visit, or to another site that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a site to recognize a user’s device. You can find more information about cookies at [**www.allaboutcookies.org**](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "All About Cookies. This opens a new window.") and [**www.youronlinechoices.eu**](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ "Your Online Choices. This opens in a new window.").

Cookies do a lot of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently and remembering your preferences, and they generally improve the user experience. They can also help to ensure that the advertisements you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.

The cookies used on this Site have been categorized on the basis of the categories found in the International Chamber of Commerce UK Cookie guide issued in April 2012. A list of the types of cookies used by State Street is set out below.

Some of our cookies are used for web analytics and intelligence about our Site. This information may be combined with other information for the purposes described below, including marketing. We may also use web beacons or other technologies for similar purposes and we may include these in marketing email messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and links clicked on. Web beacons do not place information on your device, but may work in conjunction with cookies to monitor online activity.

## **What if I don’t want cookies or website tracking of my activities?**

By using our Site you agree that we can place cookies on your device and use other online tracking mechanisms as explained in this Privacy Notice. If you want to remove existing cookies from your device, you can do this using your browser options. If you want to block future cookies being placed on your device, you can change your browser settings to do this. For more information on managing cookies and other tracking devices see [**www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies**](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/ "All About Cookies. This opens a new window.") **.**

Deleting and blocking cookies will have an impact on your user experience as parts of the Site may no longer work. Unless you have adjusted your browser settings to block cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon you visit our Site, even if you have previously deleted our cookies. To learn more about deleting or disabling cookies on your device, [click here](http://www.statestreet.com/content/ssbsr/en_US/utility/cookie-management.html).

## **What types of cookies are there and which ones does the Site use?**

There are four types of cookies explained below. We use three of them on our Site: Strictly necessary cookies, Performance cookies, and Functionality cookies. We do _not_ use Targeting cookies on our Site; however, while on our Site you may visit other sites and encounter them there. **

Strictly necessary cookies -

** These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Site and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Site. Without these cookies, services you have asked for cannot be provided.

We categorize the following cookies as strictly necessary:

1\. Registered Visitor Cookie - A unique identifier given to each registered user, used to recognize them through their visit and when they return to the Site (see also Functionality cookies below).

**Performance cookies -** These cookies collect information about how visitors use a site, for instance which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don’t collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is anonymous and is only used to improve how a site works.

We categorize the following as performance cookies:

1\. Referrer URL (internal page) - Used to store the URL of the previous page visited. Allows us to track how visitors navigate through our Site.

2\. Referrer URL - Used to store the URL which refers a visitor to our Site so we may understand what URLs are referring visitors to our Site.

3\. URL history - Used to store the page visited by a user before that user submits a form. Also, used to display recently viewed articles to each visitor.

4\. Unregistered Visitor Cookie - A unique identifier given to each visitor to allow analysis on how unregistered visitors use our Site.

Session management cookies - These cookies allow us to follow the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser window and finishes when they close their browser window. Our session management cookies are created temporarily. Once you close your browser, our session management cookies are deleted.

**Functionality cookies -** These cookies allow a site to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language, or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. For instance, a site may be able to provide you with local information by storing in a cookie the region in which you are currently located. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, font, and other parts of web pages that you can customize. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. We may use information collected from our cookies to identify user behavior and to serve content and information on products and services based on your profile. We may pass or share this information within State Street or with affiliates for marketing or analysis purposes. In most cases we will not be able to track individuals by name; only if you are a registered user we can associate the cookie information with your name.

These cookies cannot track your browsing activity on other websites. They don’t gather any information about you that could be used for online advertising on other sites or remembering where you’ve been on the internet outside our Site.

We categorize the following as functionality cookies:

1\. Recently viewed pages - Stores pages visited by the user on our Site and displays them in right-hand navigation for easy reference.

2\. Search history - Stores searches on our Site conducted by the user and displays them for the user in the right-hand navigation for easy reference.

3\. Registered Visitor Cookie - A unique identifier given to each registered user to our Site, or each user who voluntarily provides personal information on our Site to request information from us, used to serve them content and offers based on their profiles. Also used for analysis and marketing purposes (see also Strictly necessary cookies above).

**  
Targeting cookies -** These cookies are used to deliver online advertisements on other websites that are more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see such advertisements as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the site operator’s permission. They remember that you have visited a site, and this information is shared with other organizations such as advertisers. Quite often they will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organization.

As mentioned above, we do not currently use Targeting cookies on this website.

## **Third-party tracking on other websites**

A third-party cookie is one that is placed on a user’s hard disk by a website from a domain other than the one a user is visiting.

For instance, third-party social media networks may log information about you if you take certain actions on our Site, for example if you click an “Add This” or “Like” button for a social media site while on our Site. We do not control such sites or their activities. You may be able to find information about social media sites on the sites themselves. We recommend you read the terms of use and privacy policy of such sites before using them.

## **‘Do Not Track’ disclosure**

Do Not Track (DNT) is a technology standard that is currently under development that will allow you to restrict tracking when browsing from site to site on the web. When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in browsers that support this feature, the browser sends an automated browser signal to the websites and other web services (such as analytics services, advertising networks, and social platforms) you encounter while browsing to prohibit tracking.

At this time, State Street does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, such as “do not track” requests.

## **How we transfer and store personal information**

State Street is a global organization; personal information we collect may be transferred internationally throughout the world to countries where State Street does business, which may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you reside. We have internal policies and procedures in place in an effort to achieve an equivalent level of protection across our organization. The transfer of personal information to other countries is based on a business need or to comply with applicable laws. Personal information stored or processed in a foreign jurisdiction may be accessed under a lawful order made in that jurisdiction.

By providing your information to State Street in the course of your access and use of the Site or the Services, you agree that your personal information, for the purposes explained in this Privacy Notice, may be transferred to and stored in other countries where State Street does business, which may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you reside.

## **How we protect your personal information**

We use security measures, in compliance with applicable law, to protect personal information from unauthorized access or use.

To safeguard against unauthorized access to personal information by third parties, all electronic personal information held by State Street is maintained on systems protected by secure network architectures that contain firewalls and intrusion-detection devices. The servers holding personal information are “backed up” (i.e., recorded) on a regular basis in an effort to avoid any inadvertent erasure or destruction of such personal information and are stored in facilities with appropriate security and fire-detection and response systems.

When you contact State Street with questions about the Site or the Services, we must confirm your identity on the phone before discussing your information. The questions and answers you select when logging in to the Site for the first time are used for this identification process.

This Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the sites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these sites, please note that these sites have their own privacy notices or practices and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these notices, practices, or sites. Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to these sites.

## **Your rights**

As a person who provides State Street with personal information, you may inquire as to the nature of the personal information stored at and/or processed by State Street. You will be provided reasonable access to your personal information held by State Street and, where appropriate, with the ability to review and correct inaccuracies. State Street will cooperate in providing such access. All such requests for access may be made by submitting your Personal Data Access Request via the [Contact Us form](http://www.statestreet.com/content/ssbsr/en_US/contact-us.html).

To help protect your privacy and provide security, State Street takes reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to information. State Street shall respond to such reasonable requests made by you within such time period as required under applicable law after your identity has been confirmed and you have clarified the specific personal information that you require. If you demonstrate that the purpose for which the personal information is being processed is no longer legal or appropriate, the personal information will be deleted, unless the law or applicable data-retention requirements require otherwise.

## **How to contact us**

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, or about how your data is processed, please Contact Us here.

Effective date: December 31, 2016    
Last reviewed: May 30, 2019
